本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
翻译：小憨加油    王大可   杨一勾  martin008  charl
翻译：feilixiaozi   杨爱菜   某羽  校对：油炸电风扇   杨一勾
时间轴：youliss  今  spohy
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第十二集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
迈克・罗斯是个骗子  我保证
Mike ross is a fraud, and I'm gonna make sure
会让他再也看不到法庭是什么样子
he never sees the inside of a courtroom again
除非他穿上那件橙色的囚服上庭受审
unless he's wearing an orange jumpsuit.
那女人无法从起诉
That woman doesn't get anything
你这样一个骗子中得到任何东西
by prosecuting a fraud like you,
但她会很乐意抓住哈维・斯佩克特的
but she would love to get Harvey Specter.
我不会背叛哈维的
I'm not turning on Harvey.
你最好听我的
You gotta listen to me!
因为我抛给了你一条救生索
I'm throwing you a goddamn lifeline!
我也想告诉杰夫有关迈克・罗斯的事情
I want to tell Jeff the truth about Mike Ross.
他告诉你他爱你  是不是
He told you he loved you, didn't he?
我只是不想再对他说谎了
I just don't want to lie to him anymore.
你所说的关于路易把他名字弄上墙的办法
Your whole story about how Louis got his name on the door
都是瞎扯的
is bullshit!
我是来跟你说实话的
And I came here to tell you the truth.
都完了  我们结束了
It's over. We're done.
我从没想过
Never even thought for a second
你甚至会考虑
that you would even consider
背叛哈维那么恶心的想法
an idea so disgusting as turning on Harvey.
唯一能让我考虑它的原因就是
The only reason I thought about it
因为我害怕你会进监狱  怕得要死
is because I am scared to death of you going to prison.
我特地告诉你离迈克的案子远一点
I explicitly told you to stay away from Mike's case.
我不在乎
I don't care.
唐娜  你好像没懂
Donna, I don't think you get it.
总有一天你要在
There is going to come a time where you're gonna
自己和他们之间做出选择
have to choose between yourself and them.
要是他们想冲着我来  随他们来
If they're gonna come for me, they're gonna come for me.
你是说你要回来为我工作
Are you saying you're coming back to me?
是的  我愿意
Yes, I am.
那我们明早办公室见
Then I'll see you back in the office tomorrow.
爸爸  你知道我必须练习
Dad, you know I have to practice.
我知道  亲爱的
I know you do, sweetheart,
但有些事我必须告诉你
But there's something I have to tell you.
什么事
What is it?
我们要搬去康涅迪克州了
We're moving to Connecticut.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
我和你母亲认为这是对你最好的选择
Your mom and I think it's best for you.
如果那对我不是最好的呢
And what if it's not best for me?
宝贝  那是的
Honey, it is.
而且我在哈特福德市外找到了一间很好的公寓
And I found us a great apartment just outside Hartford.
有很多孩子  你肯定会喜欢的
Lot more kids. You're gonna love it.
一间公寓
An apartment.
是的
That's right.
那会比这个又大又老的房子好多了
It's gonna be so much better than this big, creaky--
你肯定有事瞒着我
There's something you're not telling me.
不  没有
No, there isn't.
一定有
Yes, there is.
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
我也不知道
I don't know,
但我就是知道
But I do.
好吧  唐娜
Oh, okay, Donna.
我的生意  不太顺利
My...business hasn't worked out,
你的叔叔为我找了一份工作
and your uncle offered me a job.
对不起  亲爱的
I'm so sorry, honey.
没事的  爸爸
It's okay, daddy.
那你继续练习吧
I'll let you practice.
爸爸
Dad?
那里有地方放我的钢琴吗
Will there be a room for my piano?
亲爱的  恐怕没有
Honey, I'm afraid there won't be.
但你的婶婶就在距离几个镇的地方
But your aunt teaches musical theater
教音乐剧
just a few towns away.
我已经给你报名了
I've already signed you up.
谢谢  爸爸
Thanks, daddy.
鲍尔森女士
Ms. Paulsen.
你想喝点什么吗
Could I get you a drink?
我在这里的时间不会够喝什么的
I'm not gonna be here long enough to finish it.
直到我同意你离开前你都要待在这里
Oh, you're gonna be here till I tell you you can go.
那你肯定要比你预期的更早同意
Which you're gonna tell me sooner than you think,
因为我没什么可说的
because I've don't have anything to say.
我懂了
I get it.
哈维・斯佩克特做你老板已经很久了
Harvey Specter was your boss for a long time--
也许还有比老板更深的关系
maybe even more than your boss--
因此  你肯定知道
In which case, there's no chance in hell
他在和迈克・罗斯
you didn't know that he was conspiring with Mike Ross
共谋违法
to break the law.
我唯一知道的是
The only thing I know is...
除非你逮捕我
that unless you're gonna arrest me,
不然我现在就要走
I'm walking out that door right now.
好吧
Good.
你跟我想象的一样难搞
You're as tough as I expected you to be,
所以你暂时可以走了
so for now, you are free to go.
我说过我不会久留的
I told you I wouldn't be here long.
你要帮我开门吗
You're gonna get the door for me?
我不是出于礼貌才为你开门的
Oh, I'm not opening the door to be polite.
我只是想看一下
I'm opening the door so I can see the look on your face
你看到对面房间里的人时的表情
when you see who's in that room across the hall.
爸爸
Dad?
你到底做了什么
What the hell did you do?
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything.
是你父亲几年前卷入了一桩
Turns out your father got himself involved
见不得人的地产交易中
in a shady real estate deal several years ago.
我父亲一辈子都没有做过什么错事
My father has never done anything wrong in his life.
就像迈克・罗斯和哈维・斯佩克特一样
Just like Mike Ross and Harvey Specter
从没做过什么错事吗
have never done anything wrong?
鲍尔森女士  也许你应该重新评估一下
Ms. Paulsen, maybe you should reassess
你生活中男人的品质了
the quality of the men in your life.
让我进去
Let me in that room.
对不起  不可能
Sorry, not possible.
但下次你见到你父亲的时候
But next time you see your father,
也许你可以向他解释你为了你的老板
maybe you explain to him you put his life on the line
而让他命悬一线
for the man you work for.
我从没想过自己会对另一个女人说这样的话
You know, I never thought that I'd say this to another woman,
但你是一个冷酷无情的婊子
but you are a cold, heartless bitch.
我是  而且我有名片
I am, and I've got a card.
还是把它放在你的包里吧
Why don't I just leave that in your purse?
万一你要是想通了
In case you change your mind
要帮我解决哈维・斯佩克特呢
about helping me out with Harvey Specter.
诉讼双雄
第五季  第十二集
当日早些时候
你在忙什么
What are you working on?
我只是在想吉布斯下一步会做什么
I'm just trying to figure out what Gibbs is gonna do next,
再想一下对策
figure out how to fight it.
那我能帮你做些什么吗
Is there anything I can do to help?
你可以告诉我你父亲之前
Yeah, you can tell me what your father said
让你如何处理我的事
you should do about me.
那会有什么帮助
How would that help?
因为如果我在担心这件事的话
Because I can't really focus on this
就无法集中精力做别的
while I'm worrying about that.
他让我照照镜子
He told me to look in the mirror.
然后呢
And?
你还希望他作何反应  迈克
How do you expect him to react, Mike?
他很生气  很受伤  而且
He's angry and he's hurt, and--
瑞秋
Rachel.
他让我甩了你
He told me to get rid of you.
好吧
Good.
好什么
Why good?
因为你告诉我无论如何你都会陪着我的
Because you told me that you would stay with me no matter what,
如果你瞒着我这些事
and when you keep things like that from me,
我就会怀疑
it makes me wonder.
但当你告诉我并且让我看到你的眼神时
But when you tell me and I see that look in your eyes,
就不会了
I don't.
利特先生  我已经安顿好了
Mr. Litt, I'm all settled in.
我只想说
I just wanted to say
我很高兴能跟随你...
that I'm so thrilled to be a part of your te--
是啊  你乐的跟开口蚌似的
Yeah, you're happy as a clam.
我们先说清楚一件事
Let's get one thing straight.
你或许在哈维那里成功代替了唐娜
You may have filled Donna's shoes with Harvey,
但要想让我满意可没那么容易
but it's not gonna be that easy filling them with me.
你想来硬的就来吧
Well, if that's how you want to play it.
我早就料到了  你的事我都听说了
I already know that. I heard all about you.
是吗  唐娜说的吗
Yeah? From Donna?
诺玛说的
From Norma.
什么
What?
你认识诺玛
You knew Norma?
没错
Damn skippy.
过去三十年  我和她
Played mah-jongg with that woman
每周二晚上都一起打麻将
every Tuesday night for the last 30 years.
81号街菲尔斯坦棋牌社
Mrs. Fillstein's Game on 81st street?
就是那家
The very one.
我一直想去那家棋牌社
I've been trying to get into that game forever.
你知道是她一直不让他们放你进来的吧
You know she kept you out, right?
是诺玛不让我进去的吗
Norma did that to me?
也不能怪她
Well, I can't say as I blame her.
她说那是每周最平静的一晚
Said it was her only peaceful night of the week.
我进来30秒就懂她的意思了
30 seconds in, I can see what she means.
但你还有补救的机会
But you could turn this around.
你对我好点  我能帮你说好话
Play your tiles right with me, I could put in a word for you.
你做什么我都感激不尽
Oh, anything you could do would be so appreciated.
这才像话
Yeah. That's more like it.
我还能更好呢
I can do even better.
你今天就放假回家吧
Please, make yourself at home. Take the day.
那样的话  我们就明早见了
Well, in that case, I'll see you tomorrow morning,
明早见
bright and early.
-你来了  -是啊
- You're here. - I am.
很高兴你回来了  哈维
It's good to have you back, Harvey.
回来我也很高兴  唐娜
Good to be back, Donna.
好了  多愁善感够了
All right, enough sentimentality.
你得...
I need you to--
推掉你接下来两个月的安排  已经搞定了
Clear your schedule for the next two months? Done.
一半活给了支持你的合伙人
I also gave half your business to the partners that backed you
其余的给了杰西卡和路易
and the rest to Jessica and Louis.
我可没让你这么干
I didn't ask you to do that.
是没有  你只让我当回你的秘书
No, you asked me to come back to your desk.
此话不假
I sure as hell did.
接下来呢
What's next?
接下来把迈克叫来
What's next is, get Mike into this office,
可别让他穿的太随意
and I don't want him wearing casual clothes;
让他把超人战袍穿上
I want him with his superman outfit on.
他需要的可不只
He's gonna need a hell of a lot more
斗篷和紧身衣  因为我刚刚收到
than a cape and some tights, because I just got
联邦检察官办公室的快递
a special delivery from the U.S. Attorney's office.
你可别告诉我她申请了查看所有
Don't tell me; she's issued subpoenas
迈克经手过案件的传票
for every case Mike's ever touched.
她申请的是查看我们律所
She issued subpoenas for anything
所有人经手过的案件资料的传票
anyone at this firm has ever touched.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是他们的目标不只是迈克了
It means they're not just after Mike anymore.
他们正式盯上了我们所有人
They're officially coming after all of us.
迈克已经来了  我去叫他
Mike's already here. I'll get him.
我告诉你  哈维  这招可不是儿戏
I'm telling you, Harvey, this move is no joke.
要是让那个女人进门  她就会找出些什么
That woman gets in the door, she will find something
逼迫某个人说出她想听的话
to pressure someone into saying whatever she wants,
要是我放任她在我的地盘撒野那就见鬼了
and I'll be damned if I'll let her rifle through my house.
你是什么意思
What exactly are you saying?
我的意思是我们需要外部律师
I'm saying we need outside counsel.
绝对不行  我们不能相信任何人
Absolutely not. There's nobody we can trust.
有个人可以信
There is one person we can trust,
因为你已经把迈克的破秘密告诉她了
because you already told her Mike's goddamn secret.
杰西卡  我不会把斯科特牵扯进来的
Jessica, I am not bringing Scottie into this thing.
我能搞定这件事
I'm telling you I can handle this.
你连阻止那些传票的策略都没有
You don't even have a strategy to stop these subpoenas.
好消息是我有办法
Well, then I guess it's a good thing I do.
那你就别等着人夸
Well, then why don't you stop patting yourself on the back
赶紧说吧
and start telling me what the hell it is?
我们主动出击
We go on offense.
那是什么意思
What exactly does that mean?
意思就是我们不需要证明
It means that we don't have to prove
她不能传唤我们的记录
that she can't subpoena our records;
她得证明她能传唤
She has to prove that she can.
而且她毫无证据
And she doesn't have a shred of evidence
证明你知道我的事
proving that you knew about me.
如果她能申请到那些传票
If she got those subpoenas in the first place,
那她肯定有证据
she must have something.
错  我在地检署工作了五年
Wrong, I worked in the D.A.'s office for five years.
法官发传票就像发糖一样随便
Judges give out subpoenas like candy.
那我建议你们俩赶紧去找法官
Then I suggest the two of you get the hell on down there
把那女人的糖抢走
and take that woman's candy away.
法官大人  其实她根本没有
The fact is, Your Honor, she has no grounds
申请这些传票的依据
to even issue these things in the first place.
他来干什么
What is he even doing here?
我来是因为我是个律师
I'm here because I'm a lawyer
在背叛有罪之前  我都是清白的
and I'm innocent until proven guilty.
那些传票根本不是冲我来的
And those subpoenas aren't about coming after me;
而是冲着他去的
They're about coming after him.
一点没错  因为他不可能
You're damn right they are, because there's no way
不知道你是个骗子
he didn't know you're a fraud.
那你证明这些话的证据在哪儿
Where exactly is your evidence of either one of those things?
我懂了  你们不是想撤销那些传票
I see. They're not trying to fight these subpoenas.
而是想让我交出手上的所有证据
They're trying to get me to turn over whatever evidence I have,
而我只需在三周后上交即可
which I don't have to do for another three weeks.
我说什么你就得做什么
You'll do whatever I say you have to do.
现在我想知道这一切的起因是什么
Now, I want to know what started this whole thing.
一位有名望的线人发来一封匿名邮件
We received an anonymous email from a reputable source.
前几天还有个陌生人打电话给我
Yeah, and a stranger called me the other day
说你杀了六个人
saying you killed six people.
我能传唤她的银行记录吗
Can I subpoena her bank records?
你当这是儿戏吗
You think this is a joke?
你知道这不是儿戏就好
You're damn right this isn't a joke.
因为一封没人见过的破邮件
I'm being accused of a crime based on some bullshit email
我就被指控犯罪了
no one's even seen.
我得问你带那封邮件了吗  吉布斯女士
I'd ask if you have that email on you, Ms. Gibbs,
我也不想认为你在骗我
but I wouldn't want to put you in the position of lying to me,
拿出来看看吧
so let's have it.
这封邮件发自哈佛普通员工邮箱
This is from a general Harvard faculty address.
确实  我们正在调查发信者的身份
It is. We are working on tracking down the sender.
你最好找到他们
Well, you'd better find them,
因为没有确切证词
because without corroborating testimony,
我不仅不会准许那些传票
I'll not only quash these subpoenas;
还会叫停整个案子
I'll toss the entire case.
混蛋  是亨利・吉拉德
Son of a bitch. It's Henry Gerard.
哈维  如果吉拉德想暴露我
Harvey, if Gerard was gonna say something,
为什么要等到现在
why would he wait until now?
不知道  但唯一可能出卖你的人
I don't know, but it's the only goddamn person
就是他
it could be.
那我去找他
All right, then I'm gonna go see him.
然后呢
And do what?
我要在吉布斯找到他之前找到他
I'm gonna get to him before Gibbs does,
让他改变想法
get him to recant.
这不是证词
This isn't testimony.
而是对你真实犯下的罪行的举报
It's a tip to a crime you actually committed.
我不管  我们有吉拉德的把柄
I don't care. We have leverage on Gerard.
你还不懂吗
Were you in there?
这个女人对我们俩都紧盯不放
This woman has her sights on both of us.
你前脚去波士顿  她后脚就派人
You go up to Boston, she's gonna have people
把哈佛翻个底朝天
crawling all over Harvard,
那样你就会让她知道吉拉德
and you're gonna be the one who led her to Gerard.
我不能坐以待毙  等待厄运降临
I can't just sit here and wait for the sword to drop.
等一等
Wait a second.
你不能去  我也不能去
You can't go there, I can't go there,
但我知道谁能去
but I know someone who can.
杰西卡
Jessica.
我还在想你何时会来找我
I was wondering when you were gonna show up at my door.
那你听说迈克・罗斯出事了
So you've heard about Mike Ross.
没错  所有人都知道迈克・罗斯的事情
Oh, everybody's heard about Mike Ross.
现在我终于知道你一直对我隐瞒的是什么事
Now I finally know what you were hiding from me the whole time.
但是我不能理解的是
But what I don't know is how the hell
你当初为何要让它发生
you let something like this happen in the first place.
我们过一会再谈这个
We'll talk about that in a minute.
我来不仅是为我们之间的事
But I'm not just here to apologize
向你道歉
for what happened between us.
我是来寻求你的帮助
I'm here to ask for your help.
你是想让我做律所的代理律师
You want me to represent the firm.
如果事情到了那一步  我想请你做我的律师
If it comes to it, I want you to represent me.
你到此向我提出如此要求脸皮可真够厚
You got a lot of nerve coming in here to ask me that.
杰夫  求你了
Jeff, please.
我曾经因为没有信任你而犯错
I made the mistake of not trusting you once.
我不想再犯同样的错误
I don't want to make that same mistake again.
那你必须告诉我一切事情的真相
Then you're gonna have to tell me the truth about everything
立刻  而且你我的谈话
right now, and it's not gonna be protected
不受律师与当事人保密协议的保护
by attorney-client privilege,
而且你必须相信我不会出卖你
And you're gonna have to trust that I'm not gonna turn you in.
我从未担心过你会出卖我
I was never worried that you were gonna turn me in.
我是担心把你置身于一个难堪的境地
I was worried about putting you in a position
让你不得不为此而撒谎
where you had to lie.
可反正我在那天晚上就准备好要告诉你
But I was ready to tell you that night anyway,
所以现在告诉你也无妨
so I might as well tell you now.
瑞秋  发生什么事了
Rachel, what's going on?
我刚刚接到了一通电话
I just got a call.
他们把唐娜带去联邦检察官办公室了
They took Donna down to the U.S. Attorney's office.
我们必须马上赶过去
We have to get down there right now.
我们不去  我来处理她的事
No, we don't. I'm gonna take care of her.
你继续做我们之前计划好要做的事情
You go ahead and do what we were gonna do together.
哈维  唐娜被带走改变了所有状况
Harvey, Donna getting taken in changes everything.
什么都没有改变  不要再说了
It changes nothing, so stop talking to me
去做你的事情
and do what you have to do.
-是亨利・吉拉德  -什么
- It was Henry Gerard. - What?
检举我的那个人是亨利・吉拉德
The person who handed me in was Henry Gerard.
是一封匿名邮件
It was an anonymous email.
不可能  他怎么会知道你不是一名律师
No way. How would he even know that you're not a lawyer?
去年我们接手的一个案子  他发现了破绽
That case we took last year, he figured it out.
那为何他要等到现在才举报你
Well, then why would he wait to turn you in now?
我不知道  但我知道的是
I don't know, but what I do know is,
你必须赶往波士顿  让他撤回指控
you need to get up there and you need to get him to take it back.
这我怎么办得到
How the hell am I supposed to do that?
这是你和我必须马上解决的事情
That's what you and I are gonna figure out right now.
等一等  哈维去哪儿了
Wait a second. Where's Harvey?
他去参加了一个重要的会议
He's got an important meeting that--
还有什么事情比这件事情重要
What could be more important than this?
路易  是一件私事
Louis, it's a personal matter--
他在哪儿
Where is he?
他们把唐娜抓去问话了
They brought Donna in for questioning.
该死的  我就害怕发生这种事
Goddamn it, this is what I was afraid of.
我马上赶过去
I'm heading down there right now.
路易  路易  听我说
Louis--Louis, listen to me.
他们会试着对唐娜施压
They're gonna try and put pressure on Donna
让她出卖哈维
to turn on Harvey, and the best way
消除胁迫的最好办法就是摆平吉拉德
to make that pressure go away is to make Gerard go away,
这样也可以解决掉整件事情
which can make this whole case go away.
把那封该死的邮件给我
Give me the goddamn email.
现在  在去之前  我们必须...
Now, before you go up there, we're gonna--
对不起  等一下
I'm sorry. Wait a second.
为何会有明知你犯罪的人
Why would someone who knows you're guilty
把你说成是"潜在的"骗子
call you a "potential" fraud?
我不知道
I-I don't know.
他可能是想保护他自己
He's trying to cover his ass somehow.
"一个潜在的诈骗犯玷污了
"A potential fraud besmirching the sacrosanct name
哈佛大学圣洁的名声"
of hallowed Harvard University"--
路易  我们真的没有时间了  拜托
Louis, we really don't have time for this. Please.
迈克  我知道是谁写的这封邮件
Mike, I know who wrote this email.
不是亨利・吉拉德
It's not Henry Gerard.
打扰一下  小姐
Excuse me, miss.
一个人吗  我可以和你坐在一起吗
Are you alone, or can an old man pull up a seat?
您好  爸爸
Hi, dad.
你有没有仔细看这份协议
So have you looked over the deal?
我看过了
I have.
你看出来我对你说过的潜力了吗
And you see the potential I'm talking about?
的确是一个好项目
It's a great project.
但是呢
But?
我不确定你再回去参与开发
I'm not sure how wise it is
是不是一个明智的决定
for you to get back into development.
我能理解在它对你造成的影响之后
I understand you would feel that way
你会这样想  但是
after what it did to you, but--
我会这样想是因为它对你造成的影响
I feel that way because of what it did to you.
唐娜  我对你说过
Donna, I told you.
现在的银行很痴迷这种事情
the banks are crazy for this kind of thing right now.
我只需要二十五万美金
All I need is $250,000.
我就能申请到五倍数额的贷款
I can get a loan five times the size.
我不知道  听上去真的很冒险
I don't know; that just sounds really risky.
你不是总告诉我  哈维说过
Aren't you always telling me that Harvey says
如果你想出人头地  必须学会冒险
if you want to get ahead, you need to take risks?
这才是你来找我的原因
That's why you came to me.
你不是想要我的钱  而是想要哈维的钱
You're not looking for my money; you're looking for Harvey's.
只是为了确保能得到那笔贷款
It would just be to secure the loan.
银行把钱给我后  就与他没有任何关系
After the bank gives me the money, he's free and clear.
哈维绝对不会同意那样的事
Harvey's never gonna go for that.
我是说  就连我都知道那不合法
I mean, even I know that's not legal.
唐娜  总有人在做这种事
Donna, people do this kind of thing all the time.
这就是一种戏法  仅此而已
It's a sleight of hand, nothing more.
爸爸  你现在干得不错
Dad, you're doing fine.
你真的有必要再冒一次险吗
Do you really need to risk everything again?
唐娜  我经营一家房地产公司
Donna, I manage a real estate office.
那里所有人都赚得比我多  干得都比我好
Everybody there makes more. Everybody there is doing better.
我曾经干得更好
I used to be better.
我知道我能办到
I know I can do this.
求你  你只需要问问哈维
Please, all you have to do is ask Harvey.
如果他拒绝  那就算了
If he says no, he says no.
爸爸  对不起
Dad, I'm so sorry.
别担心  宝贝
Don't worry, sweetie.
我受过很多人很多骚扰
People have tried to rattle my cage plenty of times.
他们以前都没成功过  这次也不会成功
It's never worked before, and it's not gonna work now.
我就这样对她说的  你不会有事
That's what I told her. You're gonna be okay.
唐娜  能让我们单独谈谈吗
Donna, can you give us a minute?
哈维
Harvey...
什么事
Yeah?
他们说这与我在七年前对你提到过的
They're saying this has to do with that deal
那份协议有关
I talked to you about seven years ago.
然后呢
And?
你是不是有什么事没有告诉我
Is there something you're not telling me?
我唯一没有告诉你的事
The only thing I haven't told you
就是我会把他救出来  不惜一切代价
is that I'm gonna get him out of this, no matter what.
你到底干了些什么
What the hell did you do?
你在说些什么
What are you talking about?
你要是七年前没做什么坏事
They didn't bring you in here
他们也不会带你过来
if you didn't do something seven years ago,
如果要我帮你脱身
and if I'm gonna get you out of this,
我得知道你到底做了什么
I need to know what you did.
我做了别人都做的事
I did what everybody else did.
我夸大了抵押品的价值  因为你拒绝了我
I inflated my collateral because you shut me down,
所以别跑过来告诉我这都是我的错
so don't come in here telling me this is my fault.
我之所以拒绝你
I shut you down to protect Donna
就是为了避免唐娜陷入这样的局面
from getting involved in exactly something like this.
这是你的错  不是我的
This is on you, not on me.
你就这么趾高气扬地跑过来
Well, aren't you high and mighty,
指责我将我的女儿置于险境
coming in here accusing me of putting my daughter at risk
而她之所以落到这一步的原因
when the whole reason she's in the position she's in
却是因为你的一些作为
is because of something you did?
没错
That's right.
他们告诉我这些是因为他们
They told me this is because they're trying
试图让唐娜作证指控你
to get Donna to testify against you,
而他们希望我能帮他们劝说她
and they want me to help them get her to do it.
那你怎么不去呢
Then why don't you?
因为我知道这会让她为难死的
Because I know it would kill her,
而且不管你怎么想
and no matter what you may think,
我绝不会做任何伤害我女儿的事情
I would never do anything to hurt my daughter.
你跟唐娜谈过了吗
Did you talk to Donna?
我跟哈维谈过了  他说他会去
I talked to Harvey, and he said it's gonna be f--
我不关心他具体说了什么
I don't care what he says.
他们为什么事抓她的
What are they coming after her for?
迈克  哈维让我不要
Mike, Harvey asked me not to--
瑞秋  他们为什么事抓她的
Rachel, what are they coming after her for?
他们不是抓她
They're not coming after her for anything.
是抓她父亲
They're coming after her father.
什么
What?
据说他曾经涉足一些地产交易
Turns out he was involved in some sort of real estate deal
而有些交易是上不了台面的
and they're saying it wasn't on the up-and-up.
见鬼
Goddamn it!
迈克  冷静点  这没什么
Mike, calm down. It's nothing.
哈维会搞定的
Harvey's gonna get them out of it.
这就是轻微的违规
Look, it's really just a minor violation,
人们甚至不会在乎这个  如果不是因为
and no one would even care if it weren't for--
我  你打算说  如果不是因为我
Me. You were just about to say if it weren't for me.
-迈克  我  -行了
- Mike, I-- - That's it.
我要去认罪
I'm pleading guilty.
我要去接受这个从轻处罚
I'm gonna take the reduced sentence,
我会去服刑  然后这一切
I'm gonna do the time, and all of this
都会消失  永远消失
is gonna go away once and for all.
这不可行  你知道的
That's not an option, and you know it.
他们来追究唐娜父亲的唯一原因是
The only reason they went after Donna's dad
为了你背后的哈维和杰西卡
is to get to Harvey and Jessica.
如果你去认罪  你只会帮了倒忙
If you plead guilty, all you're gonna do is help them do that,
所以你要不然背叛他们俩
so you're either gonna turn on the two of them
要不然你就抗争到底
or you're gonna fight this thing out till the end.
我们得谈一下
We need to talk.
谈什么
About what?
谈谈如果控方拿到传票
About what we're going to do
我们该怎么做
if that prosecutor gets a hold of those subpoenas.
你是说要怎么处理迈克手上那封能证明
You mean what we're gonna do about the letter that Mike has
你知道他是假律师的信件
that proves you knew he was a fraud.
我就是这个意思
Yes, that's what I mean.
我猜想你应该足够聪明
I'm assuming you were smart enough
知道在他们放你出来之后就毁掉那封信
to destroy that thing the second they let you out.
而我认为你应该已经销毁了那封你让瑞秋
And I'm assuming you destroyed the affidavit
签署的证明她对于我的情况知情的宣誓书
that you had Rachel sign saying she knew the truth about me.
我没有销毁
I didn't,
但我跟路易谈过了  我们达成了共识
but I had the same conversation with Louis, we worked it out,
我过来就是要告诉你
and I'm here to tell you
你毁了你手里的文件  我就毁了我的
I will get rid of mine if you get rid of yours.
我知道你在考虑
I knew it; you're actually considering
背叛我和哈维
turning your back on me and Harvey.
我不会背叛任何人
I'm not turning my back on anyone,
但是我们都清楚你做了一些动作
but we both know you've done some things
让我开始怀疑自己是否应该继续信任你
that make me question whether or not I can trust you.
这样的话  你能做的就是
Well, then, the least you can do
在判决下达之前
is find the time to speak with my attorney
找个时间跟我的律师谈一下
before that ruling comes down.
你的律师
Your attorney?
你肯定听说过他
I'm sure you've heard of him.
他的名字是杰夫・马龙
His name's Jeff Malone.
你比我想象得还要下作
You're even lower than I thought you were,
我都没想到你能做出这种事
and I didn't even think that was possible.
像你这样道德水准的人做出这种评价
Coming from someone with your moral compass,
我就当恭维好了
I take that as a compliment.
你有什么权利
What gives you the right
去针对我秘书的父亲
to come after my secretary's father?
我不是起诉他的人
I'm not the one prosecuting him.
事实是我的一个同事
It just so happens that one of my colleagues
由于一件完全不相干的事在起诉他
is going after him on a completely unrelated matter.
放屁  你这么做就是为了
Bullshit, the only reason you're doing this
向唐娜施压  让她来指证我
is to put pressure on Donna to come after me.
既然你提起来了  法官确实说过
Well, now that you mention it, the judge did say
我得找出你跟迈克・罗斯欺诈的联系
I needed something tying you to Mike Ross's fraud
才能得到传票
in order to get those subpoenas,
也许唐娜・鲍尔森就是我要找的联系
and maybe that something is Donna Paulsen.
我得去问问她
I should ask her.
你已经问过她了
You already did ask her,
现在你操纵一个莫须有的案子
and now you're manufacturing
来指控一个无辜的人
a bullshit case against an innocent man,
我保证你会为此付出代价的
and I'm gonna make sure you pay for it.
他陷入这种境地不是因为我做了什么
He's not in here because of what I did.
是因为你做了什么
He's in here because of what you did.
与其指责我  不如好好看看自己
So instead of blaming me, take a look in the mirror,
你该做的就是承认自己犯下的错
'cause all you have to do is admit what you did,
这些都会随之而去
and all of this goes away.
路易
Louis.
你在这里干嘛
What are you doing here?
你知道的
You know why I'm here.
我来这里是为了这个
I'm here because of this.
我不知道那是什么
I don't know what that is.
邮件从头到尾都是你的语气
Please, your language is all over it.
就差签上你的名字了
You might as well have signed your name.
我想知道的是你为什么要这么做
What I want to know is why.
我当时接到一个电话  是一篇报道
I got a call about an article
关于迈克・罗斯如何飞速蹿升到合伙人的
on Mike Ross's meteoric rise to junior partner.
问题是我记得这里毕业的每个学生
Problem is, I remember every student that's ever gone here,
其中没有迈克・罗斯
and there is no Mike Ross,
我又在档案室仔细查了一遍
so I double-checked my file room,
然后我就寄出了这封信
and then I sent this.
希拉  你会毁了我的律所
Sheila, you are messing with my firm.
为什么你不先来问问我
Why didn't you come to me first?
因为我觉得没必要去问你
Because it didn't occur to me that I had to.
一派胡言
That is bullshit!
你匿名报告了这个情况
You reported it anonymously
因为你不想做坏人
because you didn't want to look bad.
你不相信我能保护你不受连累
You didn't trust me to keep you out of it.
我之所以要匿名举报  是因为
No, I reported it anonymously
我为自己任上发生这种事而感到羞愧
Because I was ashamed that it happened on my watch,
但是我不能容忍这种
but I'm not gonna stand by while somebody besmirches
败坏哈佛大学名声的行径
the good name of Harvard University.
你没有证据证明迈克・罗斯败坏了什么
You have no proof that Mike Ross besmirched anything.
你为什么要维护这种败类
Why are you defending this lowlife?
因为如果你先来找我
Because if you'd come to me first,
我本可以从一开始阻止这一切发生
I could have stopped this whole thing from happening.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
你早就知道
You knew.
希拉  求你了  你不如我了解他
Sheila, please, you don't know him like I know him.
你到底来干什么  路易
What exactly are you doing here, Louis?
我希望你收回你的指控
I want you to retract that email.
告诉他们你弄错了  你找到文件了
Tell 'em that you made a mistake; you found the file.
我做不到
I can't do that.
希拉  求你了
Sheila, please.
我们分手的时候  我强迫自己去接受
When we broke up, I forced myself to accept it,
因为最终我知道我们想要的东西不同
because ultimately I knew we wanted different things,
但我还是伤心欲绝
but it killed me,
因为我知道我们是灵魂伴侣
because I also knew that we were soul mates.
而你现在却让我做这样的事情
But the fact that you're asking me to do this...
我们才不是灵魂伴侣
We are not soul mates.
我求你了
I'm begging you.
至少不要站出来作证
At least don't come forward.
我本来就没打算站出来  路易
I never was gonna come forward, Louis.
离我远点
Now leave me alone.
我就知道你在这里
I thought I'd find you here.
你还好吗
How are you doing?
他们要给我爸爸扣上
Well, they're coming after my father
莫须有的罪名
for something he didn't do.
你觉得我还好吗
How do you think I'm doing?
对不起  你想一个人静一下吗
I'm sorry. Do you want to be alone?
不用  不好意思  我只是
No. I'm sorry. It's just--
唐娜  别这样  你在为
Donna, please, you're worried sick
你爱的人而担忧
for someone you love.
我理解
I get it.
去年我的性命交付在哈维手中的时候
It's just, last year my life was in Harvey's hands,
他说我去担心他输了会怎么样
and he told me that my worrying about what would happen
只会增加他输的可能
if he lost would only make it more likely for him to lose.
我明白  而你又无法不担心
I know, and you can't help but worry about it,
因为那是你爸爸
because it's your father.
对  我没办法
No, I can't.
你也没办法不去想
And you can't help wondering,
真的到了最坏的时候  你会怎么做
if it comes down to it, what will you do?
什么
What?
不  瑞秋  你怎么能问这样的问题
No, Rachel, how can you even ask me that?
我知道了
I get it.
因为到了最坏的时候
Because if it comes down to it,
你想要迈克考虑出卖哈维
you want Mike to consider turning on Harvey.
我不是这么说的
That's not what I said.
如果你来就是想要我
You know, if you're just here to get me
考虑出卖哈维  我现在不需要这个
to think about doing that, I don't need that right now.
不不不  唐娜  我来这里
No, no, no, Donna, I came in here
是因为我关心你  我很
because I care about you and I am--
我很抱歉我提了这件事
I'm sorry that I even brought it up.
你抱歉吗
Are you sorry?
你说什么
Excuse me?
你以为我不知道
Do you think that I don't know
只要我告诉他们这是哈维做的
that all your problems are solved
你就万事大吉了
if I tell them that Harvey did this?
不  唐娜  是迈克说了就万事大吉了
No, Donna, all of my problems are solved if Mike tells them.
但你说得对  如果哈维能敢作敢当
But, yes, my life gets a whole lot better
我的生活会好很多
if Harvey takes responsibility for what he did.
他所做的就是给迈克一个
What he did was give Mike a chance
出人头地的机会
to make something of himself.
所以迈克绝对不会出卖他的
Which is why Mike's never gonna turn on him.
但是你知道吗
But you know what?
但如果说我没有想过迈克应该做个交易
I would be lying if I said it didn't cross my mind
那是在说谎
that maybe mike should think about making a deal.
你也别告诉我从他们抓走你爸爸开始
And you can't tell me that since they picked up your father
你没有过同样的想法
that the thought hasn't crossed yours too.
想过和说出来
Well, thinking about it and talking about it
可不是一回事
aren't the same thing,
而现在  我要专注于相信哈维
and right now, I'm focusing on having faith in Harvey.
路易  怎么回事
Louis, what the hell?
我找了你一早上了
I've been looking for you all morning.
-发生什么事了  -是她
- What happened? - It was her.
然后呢
And?
她不会收回指控
She's not gonna retract the email.
见鬼  她说什么了
Shit. What did she say?
你以为她说了什么
Oh, what the hell do you think she said?
她说她知道你是个骗子
Said she knows you're a fraud,
并且不会撤回指控
she's not gonna take it back,
现在她知道我也参与了这件事
and now that she's figured out that I've been a part of it,
她连看都不想看我了
she can't stand the sight of me.
好吧  那我们得想其他办法
All right, then we need to think of something else--
你听到我刚说的话了吗
Oh, did you just hear what I just said?
她看都不想看到我了
She can't stand the sight of me.
路易  我知道你现在不好受
Louis, I know you're feeling bad,
但现在唐娜处境危险
but right now, Donna is under the gun.
你要我怎么办
What do you want me to do about that?
我不知道  但是如果她不收回邮件里的指控
I don't know, but if she doesn't retract that email
他们找到她的话
and they find her--
不会的  他们不会找到她
No, they're not gonna find her,
因为她是用教师公共邮箱发的
because she sent it from a general faculty email
因为她引以为辱  就像以我为辱一样
because she's ashamed of herself like she's ashamed of me.
而这一切都是你的错
And this is all your fault,
所以从我的办公室滚出去
so get the hell out of my office
而不是想方设法
instead of trying to figure out a way
为你自己遮掩
to cover your goddamn ass!
不管你相不相信  路易
You can believe this or not, Louis,
但这一刻
but right this second,
我其实是在帮唐娜
I'm actually looking out for Donna.
对不起  迈克
I'm sorry, Mike.
这一刻  我帮不了你
Right this second, I cannot help you.
很好  你来了
Good, you're here.
我要你去处理
Listen, I need you to take care of--
在我们讨论策略之前
Before we get to the game plan,
我需要知道唐娜的爸爸怎么样了
I need to know what's going on with Donna's father.
我在处理了
I'm taking care of it.
你叫路易去见吉拉德了吗
Did you get Louis to go see Gerard?
不是吉拉德  是希拉・赛斯
It wasn't Gerard. It was Sheila Sazs.
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
路易把你的事告诉他女朋友了
Louis told his girlfriend about you?
不  哈维  是你把我的事告诉女朋友了
No, Harvey, you told your girlfriend about me.
路易冒着生命危险去让希拉
Louis risked his neck to get Sheila
收回指控来为我们遮掩
to take that email back to save our asses.
那你这么失控又是为什么
What are you so bent out of shape for?
我失控是因为他没能做到
I'm bent out of shape because he couldn't do it,
除此之外  唐娜的爸爸是因为我们
And on top of that, Donna's dad is only in this mess
才被牵扯进来  而你却不让我帮忙
because of what we did, and you won't let me help.
说得对  迈克  我不会让你帮忙的
That's right, Mike; I won't let you help,
因为你正在因为诈骗
because you're under investigation
而接受调查
for being a fraud.
他们也在调查你
You're under investigation too,
我们要假装
and if we're supposed to act like
问心无愧的话
there's nothing to be ashamed of,
那我们就表现得问心无愧
then let's act like there's nothing to be ashamed of.
好了  你说的都对  迈克
Okay, that's all well and good, Mike,
但我才是唐娜爸爸的律师  不是你
but I'm the one representing Donna's father, not you,
也就是说只有我一个人有正当的理由
which means I'm the only one with a credible reason
去见那个最开始
to pay a visit to the banker that gave him
给他那份糟糕贷款的银行家
that shitty loan in the first place.
哈维  这让我生不如死
Harvey, this is killing me!
我必须得做点什么
I have to do something.
现在  你能做的最好的事情
Right now, the best thing you can do
就是想一下如果他们想到了
is think about what we're gonna do
路易的女朋友我们要怎么办
if they put it together about Louis's girlfriend,
因为如果他们找到她  我们就完了
because if they find her, we're in deep shit.
你怎么知道我在这里
How did you find me here?
你的案子里的每一局
I remember every game you have
我都记得
from our work on your case.
我知道我得在一个能让我们
And I knew I had to find you at a place
不被任何哈佛的人看到的地方见面
where we couldn't be bothered by anyone from Harvard.
因为现在哈佛所有人都知道你没有念过哈佛
Because everyone from Harvard now knows you didn't go there.
正因为如此我才需要一个哈佛的人
Which is why I need someone from Harvard
告诉他们我念过
to tell them that I did.
你是疯了吗
Are you crazy?
不  我理智得很
No, I'm smart.
检察官手里只有匿名举报
All they have is an anonymous tip
而没有确凿证据
and no corroborating evidence.
你在这份证明我上过你的课的证词上签字
You sign this affidavit saying that I was in your class,
整个案子都会被撤销了
their whole case gets dismissed.
如果没撤销呢
And what if it doesn't?
那我就出庭受审
Then I go to trial.
这是合理怀疑
This is reasonable doubt.
我无罪释放后  他们就拿我没办法了
I get acquitted, they can never try me again.
或者这不是合理怀疑  你被证实有罪
Or it's not reasonable doubt, you don't get acquitted,
我就得因作伪证入狱了
and I go to jail for perjury.
我还记得当时你作伪证
I remember when you were willing to commit perjury
我们不但阻止了你  还救了你一命
and we didn't just stop you; we saved your ass.
我不管  我不会为你冒这么大风险的
I don't care. I'm not risking everything for you.
这不只是为了我  好吗
This isn't just for me, all right?
他们正在追查每一个我在乎的人
They are coming after everyone that I care about.
我很同情你  迈克
I feel for you, Mike,
因此我绝对不会告发你
which is why I never turned you in in the first place,
但我没法帮你这个忙
but I can't do what you're asking.
那如果我匿名向哈佛举报
And what if I anonymously told Harvard
说你接受过一个想得高分的学生的贿赂呢
that you took a bribe from a student for a grade?
你敢赌上一切确保我不会告发你吗
You willing to bet everything that I won't do that?
你尽管去做吧
You do what you have to do,
我不会把自己的一生都置入险境
But I'm not putting my life in jeopardy
就为了签那个鬼东西
by signing that goddamn thing.
等一下  等等
Wait a minute, wait, wait.
如果我有办法能让你不用作伪证
What if I had a way that you could help me
就能帮到我呢
without having to perjure yourself?
怎么能做到
And how exactly would I do that?
就在你能力范围内
It's right in your wheelhouse.
咱们也来耍些小伎俩
We're playing poker too.
我只是...
I just--
我只需要你帮我虚张声势就行了
I just need you to help me bluff.
哈维  我得请你帮我一个忙
Harvey, I need to ask you to do something.
没问题  唐娜  我会为你做任何事情
Of course, Donna. I'd do anything for you.
其实不是为了我  是为了我爸
Well, it isn't for me. It's for my father.
他想知道你是否有意愿
He wanted to know if you would consider
投资他的房地产项目
investing in his real estate project.
抱歉  我没法帮这个忙
I'm sorry. I can't do that.
可你刚告诉我你会为我做任何事情
You just said that you would do anything for me.
我是说我会去考虑  我考虑好了
I meant I'd consider anything, and I just did.
你看都没看啊
You haven't even looked at it.
没必要看
I don't need to.
你是我的家人  他是你的家人
You're family to me, he's family to you,
而钱是不能投资给家人的
and you don't invest money with family.
马库斯因为餐厅的事需要钱时
That's not what you said when Marcus needed money
你可不是这么说的
for his restaurant.
-那不一样  -为什么
- That's different. - Why?
因为马库斯很清楚自己在干什么
Because Marcus actually knew what the hell he was doing.
哈维  你要是不想投资就算了
You know what, Harvey? If you don't want to invest, don't invest,
但我不需要你来告诉我
but I don't need a lecture from you
我爸有多不擅长经商
on what a bad businessman my father is.
你需要
Yes, you do.
是吗  为什么
Oh, really? Why's that?
因为我没猜错的话
Because if I know you,
你正在考虑把你退休金给他
you're thinking of giving him access to your 401K.
所以呢  是又怎样
So? What if I am?
唐娜  这个人曾经把你家的钱给亏光了
Donna, this man lost your family's money once.
你要给他多一次机会这么做吗
You're gonna give him the chance to do it again?
哈维  他是我爸爸
Harvey, this man is my father,
他一直都支持着我
And he has been there for me my whole life.
我知道你和你妈的事情
And I know what happened between you and your mother,
但别因为她做的事就随便判定他
but don't you judge him for what she did.
你怎么可以这样说  这和那事无关
How dare you? This has nothing to do with that.
你看他的事情是有盲点的
You have a blind spot when it comes to him.
我这是在保护你
I'm trying to protect you.
你不是在保护我  你这样做像个混蛋
Well, you're not. You're being an asshole.
提醒你一下  让我远离我爸
And for your information, keeping me from being there
才不是在保护我
for my father isn't protecting me.
而是在激怒我
It's pissing me the hell off.
太好了  唐娜你在  我需要你去...
Good, Donna, you're here. Look, I need you to--
我只想听你说你干了什么
The only thing I need is for you to tell me what you did,
因为我刚发现他们
because I just found out that they're
明天将正式以银行欺诈的罪名起诉我爸
formally charging my father with bank fraud tomorrow.
该死
Goddamn it.
你做了什么
What did you do?
我只是去逼了一个银行家
All I did was strong-arm a banker.
你为什么要去逼一个银行家
And why the hell would you need to strong-arm a banker?
因为他手上有必须除掉的证据
Because he had evidence that needed to get lost.
我就知道你有事没告诉我
I knew there was something you weren't telling me.
七年前到底发生了什么
What the hell happened seven years ago?
发生的只是  你来找我
What happened is, you came to me
让我帮你爸一个忙  于是我去找他
asking a favor for your father, so I went to him
让他帮我一个忙
asking a favor of my own.
胡说  你是不会让人帮忙的
Bullshit. You don't ask people for favors.
你只会逼他们做事
You force them to do things!
你说得太对了
You're goddamn right I do.
我告诉你爸如果他拿了你的钱
I told your father if he took your money,
我就会用尽一切手段让他的生意完蛋
I'd pull every string I have to shut his deal down.
你没权力这样做
You had no right to do that.
我不管我有没有权力这么做
I don't care if I had a right to do it or not.
我是不会任凭你失去一切
I wasn't gonna let you lose everything
只因为你没有看透他
just because you couldn't see the truth about him.
我看透的是  你没经允许掺和我的私事
The truth is, you went behind my back,
他又做了些违法的事情
and then he did something illegal,
弄得我现在要因为你们的所作所为
and now I have to choose between you and him
在你们之间做选择
because of what you did!
我做的只有
What I did was keep you
让你不趟这趟浑水
from being involved in this mess.
不  哈维  那天你一意孤行
No, Harvey, what you did was start this mess
雇了个骗子进来  制造了这趟浑水
the day you went ahead and hired a fraud.
怎么了
What happened?
他们要正式起诉唐娜的父亲了
They're formally charging Donna's father,
我们得找法子让他的案子撤回
and we need to figure out a way to get his case thrown out.
那样我们得让我的案子撤回
Well, then we have to get my case thrown out,
因为这会让他们顾不得唐娜的爸爸
Because then they won't care about Donna's dad.
那该怎么做呢
And how the hell are we gonna do that?
我去见吉拉德了
I went to see Gerard.
该死  我不是让你别这么做吗
God damn it, didn't I tell you not to do that?
那是因为之前我们不知道
That was before we knew he wasn't the one
他没告发我
that tipped them off.
那如果他没有告发你
If he wasn't the one who tipped them off,
那你找他干什么
what the hell did you go to him for?
我找他是为了这个
I went to him for this.
这是一份用词很模糊的声明
This is a vaguely worded statement.
并不能很好地说明你上过哈佛
It doesn't even specifically say you went to Harvard.
没必要说明
It doesn't have to.
这上面声称因为我掌握了他教的知识
It says that he's known me to be an amazing lawyer,
他知道我会是名杰出的律师
that I've shown mastery of the material that he teaches,
而就他所知而言
and that as far as he's concerned,
我是一名杰出的法律系学生
I'm an outstanding student of the law.
简直是狗屁
It's total bullshit.
这可不是狗屁  好吗
It's not total bullshit, all right?
如果他们没找到希拉  我们又有这个
If they don't find Sheila and we do this,
整个案子就会被驳回
we could get the whole case thrown out.
吉布斯会看穿这把戏的
Gibbs'll see right through this.
她会让吉拉德出庭作证
She'll put Gerard on the stand,
直截了当地问他
and she'll ask him point blank
他是否知道你没上过哈佛
if he knows for a fact that you never went to Harvard,
这样就等于我们判了自己死刑
and we'll have signed our own death warrant.
她不会的  因为这违反了
She's not gonna do that, because it violates
你教我的律师守则第一条
the number one rule of being a lawyer that you taught me:
不要问你不知道答案的问题
Don't ask a question that you don't have the answer to.
风险太大了
It's too big a risk.
哈维  唐娜的父亲处境危险
Harvey, Donna's dad is at risk,
而事情是因我而起
and he's at risk because of me.
唯一能让他脱身的办法就是我去告发你
The only way to get him out is to have me to turn on you
或者让整件事消失
or for us to get this whole thing thrown out,
所以你到底同不同意
so are you on board with this or not?
我们最好祈祷这招有用
We better pray this bullshit works,
不然的话  明天我们俩至少有一个
because, if it doesn't, at least one of us
要蹲监狱去了
is gonna end up in prison tomorrow.
我们要干什么
All right, what are we doing here?
法官大人  我们提出动议
Your Honor, we have a motion
撤销迈克・罗斯的案子
to dismiss Mike Ross's case.
以什么理由
On what grounds?
理由是我这里有一封来自
On the grounds that I have a letter here
哈佛法学院亨利・吉拉德教授的信
from Professor Henry Gerard of Harvard Law
称迈克・罗斯当时在他的班级中
saying that Mike Ross was in his class.
真是可笑
This is ridiculous.
就算罗斯先生在他的班级中
Even if Mr. Ross were in that class,
也不能证明他就是哈佛的注册学生
it doesn't mean he was matriculated.
但你也没有任何证据表明他不是
You still haven't shown any evidence that he wasn't,
所以有了这份文件  这个案子应该被撤销
which is why that document should get this case dismissed.
这份文件不过是
This document is
一张措辞模糊的废纸罢了
a cryptically worded piece of shit,
而且你又是个名声在外
and you're a man who has a reputation
不择手段的人
for crossing the line.
吉布斯女士  注意言辞  你想说什么
Ms. Gibbs, language. What are you implying?
法官大人  这很有可能
Your Honor, there's a good chance
是他逼吉拉德教授签的
he coerced this Professor Gerard into signing this thing.
所以我们的证物都是敲诈勒索来的
So our exhibits are all from blackmail,
只有你的证据是干净的  你是特雷莎修女啊
but yours are squeaky clean because you're Mother Teresa?
我或许不是特雷莎修女
I may not be Mother Teresa,
但我的证据肯定不是严刑逼供来的
but I don't resort to coercion to get my evidence.
那你对唐娜・鲍尔森父亲的所作所为
Then what exactly are you doing
要怎么解释
with Donna Paulsen's father?
介意告诉我他在说什么吗
Care to tell me what he's talking about?
我来告诉您  她针对一个无辜的商人
I'll tell you. She fabricated a charge
进行虚假指控  以此来给我的秘书施压
against an innocent businessman to pressure my secretary
好让她做假证指认我
into giving false testimony against me.
法官大人  找到能对付重要证人的筹码
Your Honor, it's standard practice
并不出格
to find leverage against a vital witness.
那让联邦法警在小隔间里
Oh, is it also standard practice to have
殴打我  也不出格吗
a federal marshal rough me up in a holding cell?
吉布斯女士  如果我发现有滥用职权
Ms. Gibbs, if I find out there's an abuse of power here,
那你就将是我的重点关注对象了
I will be switching my focus to you.
在您对他们的请求做出裁决之前
Then before you rule on their motion,
州检有权
the state has the right
对吉拉德教授进行提问
to question this Professor Gerard.
法官大人  我可以和吉布斯女士单独聊聊吗
Your Honor, can Ms. Gibbs and I have a minute alone?
请
Please.
你以为我不知道这封信就是在胡扯吗
You think I don't know this letter is complete bullshit?
我把这个跳梁小丑拉到庭上来
I pull this clown up on the stand,
他马上就会说实话
he's gonna tell me the truth in a minute.
这个小丑可是国内最有名的
Okay, this clown is one of
职业道德教授之一
the most distinguished ethics professors in the country.
你把他拉到庭上  这个案子会在
You put him up there, this case is over for you
你开始之前就结束
before you even get started.
那怎么现在不见他来
Then why the hell isn't he here right now
证明这事呢
verifying this thing?
因为比起他自己
Because that kid cares more about Donna Paulsen
这小子更在乎唐娜・鲍尔森
than he does about himself.
你想怎样
What do you want?
我想做个交易  这封信换唐娜的父亲
I want to make a deal-- that letter for Donna's father.
这也太便宜你了
This is too good for you.
如果你真的有吉拉德这张牌  他早就来了
If you really had Gerard, he'd be down here right now.
如果真是我说了算的话  他早就到了
If it were up to me, he'd be down here right now,
但这是迈克的决定
but this is Mike's call.
机不可失  时间不等人
This is a one-time offer, and the clock's ticking.
你还是要上庭审
You still get to go to trial,
让唐娜和他父亲置身事外
we get Donna and her father off limits,
我们俩择日再战
and we both live to fight another day.
我还要重发传票
I want my subpoenas too.
没门儿  法官说了不行
No way. Judge said no.
你要是把这件事在庭审上再说出来
You try to pull this thing out at trial,
我就把你那位教授朋友撕个稀巴烂
I will rip your professor friend to shreds.
法官大人  我和吉布斯女士已达成协议
Your honor, Ms. Gibbs and I have come to an agreement.
她放弃对詹姆斯・鲍尔森的所有指控
She's dropping all charges against James Paulsen,
我们撤回驳回此案的动议
and we withdraw our motion to dismiss.
下周见
See you next week.
俱乐部不错啊
Nice club.
新来的吗
Are you new?
随便看看  不爱打高尔夫
Just visiting. Not much of a golfer.
真不幸  我也是
Unfortunately, neither am I.
哈维・斯佩克特
Harvey Specter.
吉姆・鲍尔森
Jim Paulsen.
我猜这是关于唐娜
I assume this is about the opportunity
给你带去的那个机会
Donna brought you.
如果数字合理的话才是个机会  吉姆
It'd be an opportunity if the numbers added up, jim,
但并不合理
but they don't.
我不懂
I don't understand.
我以为你是那种
I thought you were the type of man
-愿意冒风险的人  -我是
- that was willing to take risks. - I am--
但若会置我在乎的人于险境  那就另当别论了
but not if it puts people I care about in jeopardy,
所以我来是想告诉你
which is why I'm here to tell you
如果唐娜要把她的养老金给你
that when Donna offers you her 401k,
请你拒绝
you're gonna tell her you don't need it anymore.
无意冒犯  斯佩克特先生  但我女儿
No offense, Mr. Specter, but what my daughter does
怎么处理她的钱  与你无关
with her money is none of your business.
当唐娜对你太崇拜以至于
Well, it became my business when Donna put you
她不能分辨你那满嘴胡话的时候
so far up on a pedestal that she couldn't smell
我就必须要管了
the bullshit you were dishing out.
我没有在胡说
It's not bullshit.
你有  我看过那个交易了
Yes, it is. I looked at that deal.
你不可能一点手脚都不动
There's no way you're getting the kind of money you need
就拿到那么大一笔钱
without doing something shady.
夸大点我的资产获得贷款算不上动手脚
Inflating my assets to get a loan isn't shady.
大家都这么干
Everybody does it.
大家完蛋前都是这么想的
That's what everybody thinks until the music stops,
所以如果你让唐娜牵涉其中
which is why if you involve Donna in this deal,
我发誓  我会用尽手段
so help me god, I will pull every string I have
让你的项目在法庭上绑二十年
to tie your project up in court for the next 20 years.
我只是在努力打拼罢了
I'm just trying to make my way.
我想说的只是  别连累唐娜就行
All I'm telling you is, you can make it without Donna.
你好像觉得我连自己女儿都不爱一样
You act as if you think I don't love my own daughter.
如果爱一个人的话
People who love other people
是不会置他们于违法之地的
don't put them in positions to break the law.
刚跟我爸打完电话
I just got off the phone with my dad.
他把好消息告诉了我
He told me the good news.
跟你说了  我会搞定的
I told you I'd take care of it.
你怎么做的
What did you do?
那不重要
It's not important.
哈维
Harvey.
我们撤回了撤销迈克案子的动议
We withdrew our motion to dismiss Mike's case
以此为交换让她放过你
in exchange for her leaving you alone.
所以我拖了迈克案子的后腿
So I hurt mike's case.
不  你没有
No, you didn't.
整件事都是在虚张声势罢了
The whole thing was based on a bluff
本来也站不住脚的
that never would have held up anyway.
这样  至少我们还赚了一点
This way, we at least got something for it.
谢谢你  哈维
Thank you, Harvey.
我很抱歉说了那些话
And I'm sorry for what I said.
不
No.
你说的是对的
You were right to say it.
我不该把你置于这种境地  唐娜
I never should have put you in this position, Donna.
如果你想回去为路易工作  我能理解
If you want to go back to work for Louis, I'll understand.
你是不该把我置于这种境地
No, you shouldn't have put me in that position,
但如果我要为你雇了迈克而离开你
But if I was gonna leave you for hiring Mike,
那我几年前就这么做了
the time to do that would have been years ago.
希望我没有打扰你们过早庆贺
I hope I'm not interrupting your premature celebration.
你最好不要在协议上食言
You better not be reneging on our deal.
不  我会遵守
Oh, no, I'm gonna honor it.
我只是顺路过来给你这个
I just dropped by to serve you with these.
你和你的合伙人被传讯
You and your partners are hereby subpoenaed
提供律所所有文件
to hand over every single document in the entire firm.
不
No.
法官不可能批准这个
No way the judge granted that
就为我们撤回驳回此案的动议
just because we withdrew our motion to dismiss.
她没有
She didn't.
她是在哈佛一个叫希拉・赛斯的
She granted it when a Sheila Sazs from Harvard
出现说是她写了匿名邮件之后批准的
came forward and said she wrote that anonymous email.
没错  斯佩克特先生
That's right, Mr. Specter.
你们赢下这案子的形势
Your chances of winning this case just took
急转直下了
a mighty big turn for the worse.
你来这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
你没来见我
You never came to see me,
所以我觉得我该来找找你
So I thought I would come to you
弄清楚你为什么这么愿意
and find out why you're so willing
让那些危险的信件
to let all those dangerous letters
一直在外面到处传
just keep floating around out there.
我想你是指那些会危及你客户的信件
I think you mean letters that are dangerous to your client.
我现在手里就有一封
Well, I'm holding one right here
会给你的女人招来麻烦  迈克
that puts your woman in a world of trouble, Mike,
所以  我不是那意思
So no, no, I don't.
我明白了
Oh, I get it.
我没有服从杰西卡  所以你来
I didn't crumble to Jessica, so now you're here
强迫我接受交易
to take a shot at strong-arming me into a trade.
不  我来是来看看
No, see, I came to see why,
为什么保护了你这么久的女人
when the woman that's been protecting you for so long
只要求你给一点信任
asks you for a simple gesture of trust,
你却好像认为
you seem to think that
她只是在保护自己
all she's doing is protecting herself.
因为她是在保护她自己
Because she is protecting herself.
你说得没错  她是在保护自己
You're goddamn right that's what she's doing,
但也不只是保护自己
but that's not all she's doing,
因为从她发现你的事的那一刻起
because from the second that she found out about you,
她就一直在为你说谎
she's had to lie for you,
而她一直待你如家人
and she still treated you like family,
那让她搭上了一切
and it cost her everything.
饶了我吧  到目前为止她什么也没失去
Give me a break. Until now, it didn't cost her anything.
你给我小心点
You better watch yourself.
你在做什么
What the hell are you doing?
那让她失去了跟我的感情
It cost her her relationship with me!
你不知道  是吗
You didn't know about that, did you?
现在你知道了
Well, now you do.
所以如果我给你  你会毁掉吗
So you'll destroy that if I give you mine?
我是个律师  不能毁掉证据
I'm an attorney. I can't destroy evidence.
但你  你想做什么都行
But you? You can do whatever you want.
你这么信任我吗
You trust me to do that?
不  迈克
No, Mike.
杰西卡信任你
Jessica does.
路易  我需要你坐下来
Louis, I need you to sit down.
怎么了  发生了什么
What is it? What happened?
你父亲还好吗  我现在过去
Is your father okay? I'll go down there right now.
他很好  哈维搞定了
He's fine. Harvey took care of it.
那我不需要坐下来了
Oh, well, then I don't need to sit down.
因为不管什么事  你没事我就没事
'Cause whatever it is, if you're okay, I'll be okay.
希拉站出来了
Sheila came forward.
什么
What?
她承认是她写的邮件
She admitted she was the one to write the email.
不可能
That's not possible.
她跟我保证了不会做的
She promised me she wouldn't do that.
很抱歉  路易  但她做了
I'm sorry, Louis, but she did.
我得一个人静静
I need to be alone.
路易  我觉得现在你不该...
Louis, I don't think this is the time for you to--
我说了  出去
I said get out.
他做了吗
He did it?
做了
He did.
你跟他说了什么
What did you say to him?
我告诉了他这件事让你损失了什么
I told him how much it cost you,
而后我做了我们讨论过的事
and then I did what we talked about.
那很好
Well, it's a good thing you did,
因为这些传票刚刚送来
because those subpoenas just came down.
杰西卡  我知道我一直
Jessica, I don't know that I've ever been
都不太相信神灵
much of a spiritual person,
但我的确承认
but I would be lying if I didn't admit
有时我会觉得上帝自有安排
that sometimes I think god has a plan.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
我说上帝可能是想告诉你
I'm saying that maybe he's trying to show you
在皮尔森-斯佩克特-利特律所外
that there's more to life than
生活还有很多部分
Pearson Specter Litt.
这件案子  我不会做你的律师
I'm not gonna be your attorney on this one.
我觉得你可以找到更好的
I think you can find someone better.
不
No.
我相信你  而且也不可能
I trust you, and there's no way
找到我更相信的人
I find someone that I trust more.
那就在这事结束之后来找我
Then find me when this is all over,
看看能不能把那份信任派上更好的用场
and we'll see if we can put that trust to better use.
格雷琴  无论什么都可以等明天
Gretchen, whatever it is, it can wait till tomorrow.
这个不能等
This can't wait.
我想向你道歉
I want to apologize to you.
为什么
For what?
杰克・索罗夫提名迈克・罗斯做合伙人时
When Jack Soloff nominated Mike Ross for partner,
我知道那让哈维有点受伤
I know it hurt Harvey a little,
因为他希望是他提名迈克
because he wanted to be the one to do it,
所以我给《美国律师协会杂志》打电话
so I called the "ABA Journal"
要求报道迈克
to write an article about Mike.
我是想给哈维一个惊喜
I wanted to surprise Harvey with it.
你是说那篇让希拉看出问题的文章是你弄的
You're saying the article that tipped Sheila off was you?
是的
Yes.
你为什么要告诉我
Why are you telling me this?
因为我很抱歉
Because I'm sorry.
如果有人问  我会否认说过这些
And if anyone ever asks, I'll deny ever saying this,
但  我知道你们都知道
but...I know you all knew.
我支持你们
And I'm with you.
出什么事了
What's the matter?
我知道我说过不希望你隐瞒我任何事
I know I said I don't want you to keep things from me,
而我也不想隐瞒你
but I don't want to keep things from you either.
你隐瞒了什么
What are you keeping from me?
其实有一个好消息和一个坏消息
It's actually good and bad news.
我今天有机会把这个事完全搞定
We had a chance to get this whole case thrown out today,
但最后没成功  但我们把唐娜的事搞定了
and it didn't work, but we did get Donna off,
而且这是第一次  我真的开始相信
and for the first time, I actually started to believe
我们可以解决这件事
we can get out of this thing.
那你之前为什么不敢跟我承认呢
And why were you afraid to admit that to me?
因为我不想让你燃起希望
Because I didn't want to get your hopes up.
而我之前真的没信心
And I didn't really believe it before.
怎么了
Yeah, what's up?
希拉・赛斯站出来了
Sheila Sazs came forward,
意味着他们要更强硬地迫使我们
which means they're gonna try and pit us all
所有人互相指认了
against each other even more.